# CODY BARRUS WEB DEVELOPER

- codybarrus@gmail.com
- codybarrus.com
- **4** (425) 295-4463
- **♀** Issaquah, WA
- in scbarrus
- goopscoop

I'm a web developer and science fiction author, passionate about creating things, problem solving, and telling stories. Whether it's developing the plot of a kick ass adventure novel, or developing great web apps, I find the creation process rewarding and enjoyable.

As a developer, I enjoy developing in front end, back end or full stack capacities. On the front end, I have experience with Angular.js, Materialize, and Bootstrap, designing fully responsive sites. On the back end, I've worked in Node.js, Sails, and Ruby on Rails servers using PostgreSQL and Mongo databases.

### Skills

#### FRONT END

HTMI 5

CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

Angular.js Bootstrap

Materialize.css

AJAX

JSON

#### **BACKEND**

Ruby on Rails

Node.js Express

ActiveRecord

Sequelize

PostgresSQL

MongoDB

### MISC. SKILLS

GitHub

Test Driven Development

Inbound Marketing

Ecommerce

Content Management

Writing / Publishing

# **Employment**

#### General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Student

Mar 2015 to Jun 2015

- Student in a full time, immersive training program averaging 60 hours per week.
- Created multiple full stack web projects including LunchBreak.ninja on Node.js and MemoryLn.me on Ruby on Rails.
- Worked extensively with JavaScript, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, and Angular, as well as a wide range of frameworks and libraries.

#### Away & Away Publishing

Author / Publisher

- Sold over 10,000 copies of my works in 2014.
- Wrote/published two novels: Discovering Aberration & The Gin Thief.
- Raised funds of \$3,783 through crowdfunding site Kickstarter to offset costs of editing and design (Publishing related projects have a 32.45% success rate).

#### Chair 10 Marketing

Seattle, WA

North Bend, WA

Jun 2013 to Current

Feb 2014 to Oct 2014

Apr 2012 to Dec 2013

Account Manager

- Managed SEO (Search Engine Optimization), PPC (Pay Per Click), and content marketing for clients.
- Managed advertising campaigns within AdWords, Facebook & Twitter.
- Performed various optimization tasks including keyword research, meta data optimization and content marketing.

Visible.net Kirkland, WA

Marketing Manager

- Oversaw a department of 12 marketing specialists.
   Control pay marketing product processes adjusting protesting materials we himself and classroom style client tra
- Created new marketing product, processes, educational/training materials, webinars, and classroom style client training program.
- Produced new production pipeline which reduced product delivery from 90-120 days to an average of 7-14 days.
- Performed extensive keyword research, on-site optimization, link building, social network marketing, employee training, client training & more.

# **Projects**

#### LunchBreak.Ninja

LunchBreak.ninja is a project I build in a week while in the General Assembly Web Development Immersive program. The app finds a random, highly rated restaurant within walking distance, effectively removing the conversation "Where do you want to eat?" "I don't know, where do you want to eat?" Developed from the ground up on Node.js using a Postgres database on the back end, powered by the Yelp API, with JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML and Bootstrap on the front end.

#### Memory Lane

MemoryLn.me was a group project developed by myself, Jake Rohr and Aida Mengistu. I worked as project manager while working primarily on the backend, setting up databases and working with Ruby on Rails. My contribution also included many of the features, including the ability to add blocks and choose themes in edit mode.

As product manager, we I set up a agile work flow. Due to the week long production, we kicked agile into overdrive, meeting twice a day to discuss tactics, evaluate which features to add next.

## **Education**

General Assembly
Web Development Immersive 2015

University of Washington Bachelor of Fine Arts (B.F.A.) Creative Writing 2012

Bellevue Community College Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), General Studies

### **Awards**

#### Boy Scouts of America · Eagle Scout

Feb 2002

Earned by Eagle Scout at the age of 16. This process entailed 4 years of earning achievements known as merit badges and performing a high profile service project where I raised money to network a childrens non-profit.